<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GoGoInnovate.com</title>
    <description>Gary is a passionate advocate for teaching innovation processes to young people and as well as to the business community and he is one of the biggest supporters of and advocates for the Xavier University Center for Innovation and the School of Arts and Innovation.</description>
    <link>http://gogoinnovate.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://gogoinnovate.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 17:21:06 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 17:21:06 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Accounting</title>
        <description>&lt;h4&gt;Accounting Innovation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accounting and Finance are not your typical areas of innovation.  Sometimes these are areas that some people may think hinder innovation because they include those boring but required standard reporting such as statements of cash flow, balance sheets and income statements.  There are also budgets and projections and when working for public companies there are  banks and investors that hold businesses accountable for results.  Accounting and Finance needs to be very black and white, with rules to follow and not a lot of room for creativity.  However, the rules and requirements can be followed and the numbers can be squeaky clean AND there can still be innovation in the processes and procedures.  There are many times that an accountant has the opportunity to think outside the box when performing daily, monthly and yearly tasks.  Advancing from green bar columnar pads to Excel spreadsheets has changed the time it takes to perform functions dramatically.  The more Excel skills an individual has the more productive they can be at improving the processes.   And when a routine process is time reduced, the more time there is for looking at the numbers and what they really mean to a company and look for ways to be more profitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A word of caution on creating processes that are automated and run smoothly or so you think.  If the company changes or  software changes occur or even a new account or department is added , your automated process may  no longer be accurate and sometimes months or even a year can go by and no one realizes it.  Processes for reporting  need to be reviewed and rethought on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Innovation is also found in actual activities within the accounting and finance world such as financing a capital project.  There is the traditional way of using a bank but there are also nontraditional ways that should also be explored. Accounting and Finance cannot work in a vacuum  or have a narrow focus.  They need to be aware of the activities in other departments and understand how their reporting captures those activities.  Accounting and Finance can and should be a part of decisions that involve innovation in other areas of the company.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://gogoinnovate.com/blogs/2016/06/08/accounting/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gogoinnovate.com/blogs/2016/06/08/accounting/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blogs</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Theatre</title>
        <description>&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Theater Innovation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Theater combines real people artfully presenting dialog. This combined with creative stage settings are powerful. You can learn to make better product presentations and pitches for funding of projects. I have learned that combining the theatrical arts with retail you can create trade show booths that are unique and make you more noticeable and memorable to customers. Add music and you ad even more power to you presentation or commercial.  Remember, you idea, product, selling proposition has to be repeated three times to get into the minds you want to get into.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://gogoinnovate.com/topics/2016/06/06/theater/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gogoinnovate.com/topics/2016/06/06/theater/</guid>
        
        
        <category>topics</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Production Innovation</title>
        <description>&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Production Innovation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Production innovation starts day one with your facility lay-out for production and material flow, then continues to safety improvements needed to insure a quality product. Advancements in equipment and software open the doors for creative ideas and improvement in current and future products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developing employees with talent and ability to innovate will increase productivity in the work force. This can be obtained through communication, counselling and training. Encourage ideas from employees, customers and business partners and always strive for continual improvements.  Following these steps eliminates unnecessary processes that raise manufacturing costs. &lt;br /&gt;
Moving toward innovation leads to meeting delivery dates with quality products, and satisfied customers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://gogoinnovate.com/blogs/2016/06/06/production/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gogoinnovate.com/blogs/2016/06/06/production/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blogs</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Engineering Innovation</title>
        <description>&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Engineering Innovation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engineering innovation starts with the relentless pursuit of a solution to a specific problem without personal bias and full creative freedom.  It’s an evolution of sort that starts with an initial idea of how to solve a problem with various proposed solutions that take into account ease of use, manufacturability, cost, and reliability.  Seems easy enough, right?  The reality is there are many variables to engineering innovation such as your specific training/experience, working environment, individual personality &amp;amp; attitude, management structure, to the tools being utilized within your organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you’re the first to market with a specific widget that will revolutionize the world.  It so happens the idea has a large target market, but the product flops in lieu of another product that has enormous success a year later.  What happened?  Well first-to-market doesn’t necessarily mean best-to-market.  Too often than not ideas are rushed to market by short-cutting the necessary steps along the way.  Maybe not enough time spent in the early brainstorming/ideation phase, poor marketing effort, too costly of an end product, or overly complicated mechanics that are prone to reliability issues.  The list can go on forever, but the key is to look closely at the problem you’re trying to solve.  Work closely with the end user to better understand their pain points.  Did you really address their problem with a product that’s easy to use, reliable, and affordable?  What attempts were made to educate your target market on this new engineering innovation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an engineer you need to be flexible, resourceful, creative, and open to other possibilities that might not be YOUR initial idea!  It’s important to understand that anything is possible and that the only limit is your own imagination.  Sure there are resource variables such as time and money, but other than that the sky is the limit!  Check your ego at the door, become a good listener, and use your education &amp;amp; experience to deliver a truly innovative product!  Don’t be afraid to take risks, make mistakes, and ask questions along the way.  Innovation does not exist without taking risks.  If you’re not making mistakes, you’re not trying hard enough!  It’s very important to ask questions and find resident experts in the field to help in areas where your expertise falls short.  Always remember that the design process should be focused on the simplest mechanism/design to achieve the desired end use performance…keep it simple!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another important aspects of engineering innovation is the utilization of the tools at your disposal.  The culmination of 3D modeling, finite element analysis, laser scanning, and 3D printing are game changers that allow engineers to refine the concept and get to market quicker with a better product and lower overall investment.  3D modeling &amp;amp; finite element analysis provides the engineer with a means of creating a virtual prototype that can be tested before the first physical prototype is build!  This provides for more design iterations before getting to the first physical proof-of-concept prototype.  Laser scanning provides a means to reverse engineer a product and convert the data from a physical object to CAD data.  Finally, 3D printing provides the ability to try several different concepts before making the first costly tool.  It also provides the means to present a sample to core team members and potential end-users that can help refine the concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;CAD / CAM Innovation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CAD / CAM innovation starts out as a need, a problem, or a desire.  In all cases a predisposed concept of what will satisfy or solve has probably been imagined. Often, the first concept is not the one that will ultimately win out.  Failure and frustration is a part of the process, and that is OK. For instance, the choice of material that was selected may not be appropriate, the machine(s) available may not be capable, or the software used to generate the machine code may be inadequate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, this is not a problem so much as it is an opportunity to innovate!  The need, problem, desire still exists so there is an incentive to continue.  Go back to the original concept. Can a simpler design accomplish the objective.  Is there a different process that can be used. What about a different material. Many times the actual process of creating an item may reveal opportunities for improvement.  Remember that failure and frustration is a part of the process and embrace it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://gogoinnovate.com/blogs/2016/06/06/engineering/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gogoinnovate.com/blogs/2016/06/06/engineering/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blogs</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Art</title>
        <description>&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Art Innovation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artists have a unique way of seeing the world and living in it. I visit museums and marvel at all types of art from painting to sculpture as well as video and music. You never know what creative ideas your mind will generate just from looking at things through an artist’s eyes and ears. Also take a good look at how they create their art. It may spur an idea on a better way to make something. Sometimes overlooked as an art form are retail window displays and product presentations in the store. I marvel at them and let the creativity plan seeds of future ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://gogoinnovate.com/topics/2016/06/05/art/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gogoinnovate.com/topics/2016/06/05/art/</guid>
        
        
        <category>topics</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Management</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Still being innovated!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://gogoinnovate.com/topics/2016/06/04/management/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gogoinnovate.com/topics/2016/06/04/management/</guid>
        
        
        <category>topics</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>People / Psychology</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Still being innovated!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://gogoinnovate.com/topics/2016/06/04/people-psychology/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gogoinnovate.com/topics/2016/06/04/people-psychology/</guid>
        
        
        <category>topics</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3D Printing</title>
        <description>&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;3D Printing Innovation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3D printing has revolutionized the innovation process since the first SLA machine was sold by 3D Systems in the late 1980’s. Since then it has evolved into several different modalities with many different players in the market.  The top two professional grade printing companies are 3D Systems and Stratasys.  Both have a relatively large install base in most of the major corporations in the US. The technologies that exist today are Steriolithography (SLA), Digital Light Processing (DLP), Fused Deposition Modeling (FDM), Selective Laser Sintering (SLS), Selective Laser Melting (SLM), Electronic Beam Melting (EBM), and Laminated Object Manufacturing (LOM).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the above technologies work based on the principle of layer slice.  A 3D solid model is broken down into the layers that define the model in a given cross-section.  The printer will reproduce the layers until you end up with the completed part.  There are many factors that go into the production of a good part for your specific application.  For example, build orientation is key to part strength.  If you build a shaft down the round cross-section it will be more accurate than building it perpendicular to the cross-section (which looks like a rectangle), however, not as strong.  There are many material options that closely simulate the performance of actual molded or cast parts. It all comes down to the specific application for your part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The type of technology you choose depends a lot on what you plan to do with the end prototype and the amount of money you want to spend.  Technology such as FDM can produce very strong parts that are perfect for proof-of-concept or even end-use models.  The trade off with FDM is the aesthetic appeal of the part.  SLA is a better option if surface finish is important.  However, even with SLA a certain amount of post-processing will be necessary if your end goal is a perfect looking part.  With that being said FDM is significantly cheaper than SLA.  So there are trade-offs that must be considered with the different technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what modality you choose 3D Printing is a game changer in getting to market quicker with a better end product.  It’s hard to imagine the challenges that folks like Henry Ford must have endured in product development.  We now have the luxury of trying many iterations of a part without making tools or machining large billets of aluminum to ultimately determine a change must be made.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://gogoinnovate.com/topics/2016/06/03/three-d-printing/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gogoinnovate.com/topics/2016/06/03/three-d-printing/</guid>
        
        
        <category>topics</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3D Printing Innovation</title>
        <description>&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;3D Printing Innovation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3D printing has revolutionized the innovation process since the first SLA machine was sold by 3D Systems in the late 1980’s. Since then it has evolved into several different modalities with many different players in the market.  The top two professional grade printing companies are 3D Systems and Stratasys.  Both have a relatively large install base in most of the major corporations in the US. The technologies that exist today are Steriolithography (SLA), Digital Light Processing (DLP), Fused Deposition Modeling (FDM), Selective Laser Sintering (SLS), Selective Laser Melting (SLM), Electronic Beam Melting (EBM), and Laminated Object Manufacturing (LOM).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the above technologies work based on the principle of layer slice.  A 3D solid model is broken down into the layers that define the model in a given cross-section.  The printer will reproduce the layers until you end up with the completed part.  There are many factors that go into the production of a good part for your specific application.  For example, build orientation is key to part strength.  If you build a shaft down the round cross-section it will be more accurate than building it perpendicular to the cross-section (which looks like a rectangle), however, not as strong.  There are many material options that closely simulate the performance of actual molded or cast parts. It all comes down to the specific application for your part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The type of technology you choose depends a lot on what you plan to do with the end prototype and the amount of money you want to spend.  Technology such as FDM can produce very strong parts that are perfect for proof-of-concept or even end-use models.  The trade off with FDM is the aesthetic appeal of the part.  SLA is a better option if surface finish is important.  However, even with SLA a certain amount of post-processing will be necessary if your end goal is a perfect looking part.  With that being said FDM is significantly cheaper than SLA.  So there are trade-offs that must be considered with the different technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what modality you choose 3D Printing is a game changer in getting to market quicker with a better end product.  It’s hard to imagine the challenges that folks like Henry Ford must have endured in product development.  We now have the luxury of trying many iterations of a part without making tools or machining large billets of aluminum to ultimately determine a change must be made.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://gogoinnovate.com/blogs/2016/06/03/three-d-printing/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gogoinnovate.com/blogs/2016/06/03/three-d-printing/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blogs</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Engineering</title>
        <description>&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Engineering Innovation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engineering innovation starts with the relentless pursuit of a solution to a specific problem without personal bias and full creative freedom.  It’s an evolution of sort that starts with an initial idea of how to solve a problem with various proposed solutions that take into account ease of use, manufacturability, cost, and reliability.  Seems easy enough, right?  The reality is there are many variables to engineering innovation such as your specific training/experience, working environment, individual personality &amp;amp; attitude, management structure, to the tools being utilized within your organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you’re the first to market with a specific widget that will revolutionize the world.  It so happens the idea has a large target market, but the product flops in lieu of another product that has enormous success a year later.  What happened?  Well first-to-market doesn’t necessarily mean best-to-market.  Too often than not ideas are rushed to market by short-cutting the necessary steps along the way.  Maybe not enough time spent in the early brainstorming/ideation phase, poor marketing effort, too costly of an end product, or overly complicated mechanics that are prone to reliability issues.  The list can go on forever, but the key is to look closely at the problem you’re trying to solve.  Work closely with the end user to better understand their pain points.  Did you really address their problem with a product that’s easy to use, reliable, and affordable?  What attempts were made to educate your target market on this new engineering innovation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an engineer you need to be flexible, resourceful, creative, and open to other possibilities that might not be YOUR initial idea!  It’s important to understand that anything is possible and that the only limit is your own imagination.  Sure there are resource variables such as time and money, but other than that the sky is the limit!  Check your ego at the door, become a good listener, and use your education &amp;amp; experience to deliver a truly innovative product!  Don’t be afraid to take risks, make mistakes, and ask questions along the way.  Innovation does not exist without taking risks.  If you’re not making mistakes, you’re not trying hard enough!  It’s very important to ask questions and find resident experts in the field to help in areas where your expertise falls short.  Always remember that the design process should be focused on the simplest mechanism/design to achieve the desired end use performance…keep it simple!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another important aspects of engineering innovation is the utilization of the tools at your disposal.  The culmination of 3D modeling, finite element analysis, laser scanning, and 3D printing are game changers that allow engineers to refine the concept and get to market quicker with a better product and lower overall investment.  3D modeling &amp;amp; finite element analysis provides the engineer with a means of creating a virtual prototype that can be tested before the first physical prototype is build!  This provides for more design iterations before getting to the first physical proof-of-concept prototype.  Laser scanning provides a means to reverse engineer a product and convert the data from a physical object to CAD data.  Finally, 3D printing provides the ability to try several different concepts before making the first costly tool.  It also provides the means to present a sample to core team members and potential end-users that can help refine the concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;CAD / CAM Innovation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CAD / CAM innovation starts out as a need, a problem, or a desire.  In all cases a predisposed concept of what will satisfy or solve has probably been imagined. Often, the first concept is not the one that will ultimately win out.  Failure and frustration is a part of the process, and that is OK. For instance, the choice of material that was selected may not be appropriate, the machine(s) available may not be capable, or the software used to generate the machine code may be inadequate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, this is not a problem so much as it is an opportunity to innovate!  The need, problem, desire still exists so there is an incentive to continue.  Go back to the original concept. Can a simpler design accomplish the objective.  Is there a different process that can be used. What about a different material. Many times the actual process of creating an item may reveal opportunities for improvement.  Remember that failure and frustration is a part of the process and embrace it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://gogoinnovate.com/topics/2016/06/02/engineering/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gogoinnovate.com/topics/2016/06/02/engineering/</guid>
        
        
        <category>topics</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
